DECLAN RAMSAY

Skype: declandr@gmail.com Email: declandr@gmail.com

Website: https://declanramsay.co.uk
Github: https://github.com/thelucideffect



PROFILE

A recent graduate of the New Zealand School of Music, I have been working as a Web Developer on commercial projects for 2 years. Since leaving university I've gotten to work with some of the biggest names in New Zealand, helping them create beautiful and powerful web apps.

Coming from a non-Computer Science background I've used the skills from my Composition degree to compliment my work as developer, including being able to see wider patterns and implications across a codebase, an appreciation for evaluating different approaches for expressing an idea, and writing code that is consistent and harmonious to the whole.

My aim is to create applications that help people and fundamentally improve their web experiences. I am passionate about creating a web that is open, accessible, and diverse. Outside of work I am passionate about my music, having released 3 EPs, a single and an album, and I have toured NZ in 2015 and 2016. I am also beginning to catch the crossfit bug and love a good run.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Intermediate Developer

Alphero Limited (September 2016 – Present)

As an Intermediate Developer, I helped build functional and aesthetically pleasing websites. I've also been responsible for mentoring interns, overseeing feature implementation in consultation with the Technical Lead, and peer code reviews.

Languages and technologies used include: HTML5, CSS3/SASS, Javascript (including ES6 features), Ember, lodash, Knockout, Gulp, and Node.

Junior Developer

Alphero Limited (January 2015 – September 2016)

As a Junior Developer, I helped build functional and aesthetically pleasing websites. Languages and technologies used include: HTML 5, CSS 3,

SASS/LESS, NodeJS, JavaScript and Ember.

Engagement Vice President

Victoria University of Wellington Students 'Association (2014)

I led the VUWSA Engagement Team and I was responsible for ensuring that there is strong communication and opportunities for involvement between VUWSA, its members and students. I led the Engagement team and worked closely with the Clubs and Activities and Campaigns Officer. In particular I had a leading role in our get out the vote campaign "What Are You Voting For?" in the lead up to the 2014 General Election.

Tutor

Codesmashers (September 2014 – December 2014)

I worked as an early tutor for Codesmashers, teaching the basics of web development with CSS, HTML, and JQuery in an 2-day intensive. I worked with a team of developers to lead small groups of 5-10 people through the course, troubleshooting bugs, and generally assisting where needed.

SKILLS

I Know A Lot About:

- JavaScript (Including ES6)
- HTML 5
- CSS 3 + SASS
- Ember

- Responsive Web
- Git SCM
- Agile / Scrum
- Test-Driven Development

I Know A Bit About / Keen To Learn More About:

- NodeJS
- Chrome Extension Development

- Machine Learning
- Angular / React

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Music Victoria University of Wellington 2008 – 2014

Victoria Plus Award

Dame Malvina Major Foundation Arts Excellence Award